Guide to the Graham Arthur Barden Papers, 1934-1960
Graham Arthur Barden papers 1934-1960
- Series II--Education and Labor
  - 86th Congress 1959-1960
    - Joint Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations: Landrum-Griffin (Box 156, Folder 612-614)
    - Joint Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations: Landrum-Griffin--Teamsters (Folder 615)
    - Joint Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations: Landrum-Griffin--Committee Bill (Folder 616)
    - Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations: General (Folder 617)
    - Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations: H. R. 9070 (Box 157, Folder 618-624)
    - Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations: H. R. 9070 (Box 158, Folder 625-627)
    - Subcommittee on Labor Standards: General Papers (Folder 628)
    - Subcommittee on Labor Standards: Equal Pay for Women (Folder 629)
    - Subcommittee on Labor Standards: Minimum Wage (Farm and Seasonal Workers) (Folder 630)
    - Subcommittee on Labor Standards: Minimum Wage (Folder 631-633)
    - Subcommittee on Labor Standards: Minimum Wage (Box 159, Folder 634-640)
    - Subcommittee on Labor Standards: Minimum Wage (Box 160, Folder 641-644)
    - Subcommittee on Labor Standards: Minimum Wage (black notebook) (Folder 645)
    - Subcommittee on Labor Standards: Minimum Wage (Folder 646)
    - Subcommittee on Labor Standards: Minimum Wage (Box 161, Folder 647)
    - Subcommittee on Safety & Compensation: General Papers (Folder 648)
    - Subcommittee on Safety & Compensation: The Aged (Folder 649)
    - Subcommittee on Safety & Compensation: Employees (Folder 650)
    - Subcommittee on Safety & Compensation: Longshoremen & Harbor Workers Compensation Act (Folder 651)
    - Subcommittee on Safety & Compensation: Mine Safety (Folder 652)
    - Full Committee: Welfare and Pension Plan (Folder 653)
    - Full Committee: Davis-Bacon Act (Folder 654)
    - Education and Labor: Speeches--School Construction (1955-1956) (Folder 655)
    - Education and Labor: Speeches--Vocational Education (Folder 656)
    - Education and Labor: Speeches--Labor Material (Box 162, Folder 657-661)
    - Education and Labor: Clippings--Federal Aid to Education, 1951-1953 (Box 163, Folder 662)
    - Education and Labor: Federal Aid, 1954-1956 (Folder 663)
    - Education and Labor: Federal Aid, 1956-1957 (Folder 664)
    - Education and Labor: Federal Aid, 1960 (Folder 665)
    - Education and Labor: Federal Aid, 1957-1958 (Folder 666)
    - Education and Labor: Clippings--Federal Aid to Education, 1958 (Box 164, Folder 667)
    - Education and Labor: Clippings--Labor Reform (1959, May-Aug.) (Folder 668)
    - Education and Labor: Labor Reform (1959, Aug.-Oct.) (Folder 669)
      Note: For 1960 Clippings see folder 665, box 163. Series III--General Legislation
- Series III - General Legislation, 1935-1960
  - 74th Congress 1935-1936
    - Agriculture: (Box 165, Folder 1)
      - General
      - Agricultural Adjustment Act (Folder 2)
      - Bankhead Bill (Folder 3)
      - Cotton Cooperative (Folder 4)
      - Frazier-Lemke Farm Mortgage (Folder 5)
      - Potato Industry (Folder 6-7)
      - Tobacco Legislation (Folder 8)
    - Special Committee to Investigate Campaign Expenditures (Folder 9)
    - Immigration (Folder 10)
    - Indian Affairs (Folder 11)
    - Interstate & Foreign Commerce: Pettengill Bill (Box 166, Folder 12)
    - Interstate & Foreign Commerce: Public Utility Bill (Folder 13-15)
    - Interstate & Foreign Commerce: Railroad Pensions (Folder 16)
    - Interstate & Foreign Commerce: Trucks and Transportation (Folder 17)
    - Judiciary: Birth Control (Folder 18)
    - Pensions: Old Age (Folder 19-20)
    - Pensions: Spanish-American War Veterans (Folder 21)
    - Postal (Folder 22)
    - Rivers and Harbors (Folder 23)
    - Ways and Means: Adjusted Service Certificates (Folder 24)
    - Ways and Means: Cigarette Tax (Folder 25)
    - Ways and Means: Coal and Gasoline (Folder 26)
    - Ways and Means: Social Security (Folder 27-28)
    - Ways and Means: Miscellaneous (Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous Legislation (Folder 30)
  - 75th Congress 1937-1938
    - Agriculture: General (Box 168, Folder 31-32)
    - Agriculture: Tobacco (Folder 33)
    - Coast Guard (Folder 34)
    - District of Columbia (Folder 35)
    - Foreign Affairs (Folder 36)
    - Government Reorganization (Folder 37)
    - Immigration (Folder 38)
    - Interstate and Foreign Commerce (Folder 39)
    - Judiciary: Anti-Lynching Bill (Folder 40)
    - Judiciary: Supreme Court
    - Pensions: Old Age (Box 169, Folder 42)
    - Post Office and Civil Service (Folder 43)
    - Public Works (Folder 44)
    - Rivers and Harbors (Folder 45)
    - TVA Committee (Box 169, Folder 46)
    - Veterans (Folder 47)
    - Ways and Means (Folder 48)
    - Miscellaneous Legislation (Folder 49-53)
    - Miscellaneous Legislation (Box 170, Folder 54)
  - 76th Congress 1939-1940
    - Agriculture (Folder 55)
    - Appropriations (Folder 56)
    - Armed Services (Folder 57)
    - Banking and Currency (Folder 58)
    - Commerce (Folder 59)
    - Foreign Affairs (Folder 60)
    - Government Operations (Folder 61)
    - Health (Box 171, Folder 62)
    - Interior (Folder 63)
    - Judiciary (Folder 64)
    - Merchant Marine & Fisheries (Folder 65)
    - Post Office & Civil Service (Folder 66)
    - Public Works (Folder 67)
    - Rivers and Harbors (Folder 68)
    - TVA Committee (Folder 69)
    - Un-American Activities (Folder 70)
    - Veterans (Folder 71)
    - Ways and Means (Folder 72)
    - Miscellaneous Legislation (Folder 73)
  - 77th Congress 1941-1942
    - Agriculture (Folder 74)
    - Armed Services (Folder 75)
    - Banking and Currency (Box 172, Folder 76)
    - Commerce (Folder 77-78)
    - Foreign Affairs (Folder 79)
    - Health (Folder 80)
    - Interior (Folder 81)
    - Merchant Marine and Fisheries (Folder 82)
    - Post Office and Civil Service (Folder 83)
    - Public Works (Folder 84)
    - Rivers and Harbors (Folder 85)
    - Un-American Activities (Folder 86)
    - Veterans (Folder 87)
    - Ways and Means (Folder 88)
    - Ways and Means (Box 173, Folder 89)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 90)
  - 78th Congress, 1943-1944
    - Agriculture (Box 173, Folder 91)
    - Appropriations (Folder 92)
    - Armed Services (Folder 93)
    - Commerce (Folder 94)
    - Foreign Affairs (Folder 95)
    - Health (Folder 96)
    - Interior (Folder 97)
    - Judiciary (Folder 98)
    - Post Office and Civil Service (Folder 99)
    - Public Works (Box 174, Folder 100)
    - Rivers and Harbors (Folder 101)
    - Un-American Activities (Folder 102)
    - Veterans (Folder 103)
    - Ways and Means (Folder 104)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 105)
  - 79th Congress, 1945-1946
    - Agriculture (Folder 106)
    - Armed Services (Folder 107)
    - Commerce (Folder 108-109)
    - Commerce (Box 175, Folder 110)
    - Foreign Affairs (Folder 111)
    - Government Operations (Folder 112)
    - Health (Folder 113)
    - Interior (Folder 114)
    - Judiciary (Folder 115)
    - Merchant Marine and Fisheries (Folder 116)
    - Post Office and Civil Service (Folder 117)
    - Public Works (Folder 118)
    - Rivers and Harbors (Folder 119)
    - Un-American Activities (Folder 120)
    - Veterans (Folder 121)
    - Ways and Means (Folder 122)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 123)
  - 80th Congress, 1947-1948
    - Agriculture (Box 176, Folder 124)
    - Armed Services (Folder 125)
    - Commerce (Folder 126)
    - Foreign Affairs (Folder 127)
    - Health (Folder 128)
    - Interior (Folder 129)
    - Judiciary (Folder 130)
    - Post Office and Civil Service (Folder 131)
    - Public Works (Box 176, Folder 132)
    - Rivers and Harbors (Folder 133)
    - Un-American Activities (Folder 134)
    - Veterans (Folder 135)
    - Ways and Means (Folder 136)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 137)
  - 81st Congress 1949-1950
    - Agriculture (Folder 138)
    - Appropriations (Folder 139)
    - Armed Services (Folder 140)
    - Commerce (Box 177, Folder 141)
    - Foreign Affairs (Folder 142)
    - Health (Folder 143)
    - Interior (Folder 144)
    - Post Office and Civil Service (Folder 145)
    - Un-American Activities (Folder 146)
    - Veterans (Folder 147)
    - Ways and Means (Folder 148)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 149)
  - 82nd Congress 1951-1952
    - Armed Services (Box 178, Folder 150)
    - Commerce (Folder 151)
    - Foreign Affairs (Folder 152)
    - Ways and Means (Folder 153)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 154)
  - 83rd Congress 1953-1954
    - General (Folder 155)
    - Agriculture (Folder 156-159)
    - Foreign Affairs (Box 179, Folder 160-161)
    - Foreign Trade (Folder 162-163)
    - Interior and Insular Affairs (Folder 164)
    - Interior and Insular Affairs (Box 180, Folder 165)
    - Interstate Commerce (Folder 166-169)
    - Judiciary: Constitutional Amendments (Folder 170)
    - Military and Defense (Box 181, Folder 171-172)
    - Post Office and Civil Service (Folder 173-176)
    - Public Housing (Box 182, Folder 177)
    - Public Power (Folder 178)
    - St. Lawrence Seaway (Box 182, Folder 179)
    - Social Security (Folder 180)
    - Un-American Activities (Folder 181)
    - Veterans (Box 183, Folder 182)
    - Ways and Means (Folder 183-186)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 184, Folder 187-189)
  - 84th Congress 1955-1956
    - Agriculture (Folder 190-192)
    - Appropriations (1955) (Box 185, Folder 193)
    - Appropriations (1956) (Folder 194)
    - Armed Services (1955) (Folder 195)
    - Armed Services (1956) (Folder 196)
    - Atomic Energy (Folder 197)
    - Banking and Currency (Folder 198-199)
    - District of Columbia (Folder 200)
    - Foreign Affairs (Folder 201-202)
    - Formosa Resolution (Folder 203-204)
    - Government Operations (Box 186, Folder 205)
    - Interior (Folder 206-207)
    - Interstate and Foreign Commerce (Folder 208-211)
    - Judiciary (Box 187, Folder 212-213)
    - Civil Rights (Folder 214)
    - Merchant Marine and Fisheries (Folder 215)
    - Post Office and Civil Service (Folder 216-218)
    - Public Works: Highway Bill (Box 188, Folder 219)
    - Public Works: General (Folder 220-224)
    - Veterans (Box 189, Folder 225-226)
    - Ways and Means: Tariff Bill (Folder 227-228)
    - Ways and Means: Social Security Bill (Folder 229)
    - Ways and Means: Tax (Folder 230)
    - Ways and Means: General (Folder 231)
    - Ways and Means: General (Box 190, Folder 232)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 233-237)
  - 85th Congress 1957-1958
    - Bills Introduced by Barden (Box 191, Folder 238)
    - Agriculture: Turkey Bills (Folder 239)
    - Agriculture: General (Folder 240-241)
    - Appropriations (Folder 242-244)
    - Armed Services (Box 192, Folder 245-246)
    - Armed Services Military Aircraft Workshop Competition Act (Folder 247-248)
    - Banking and Currency (Folder 249-250)
    - Foreign Affairs (Box 193, Folder 251-252)
    - Government Operations (Folder 253)
    - Interior and Insular Affairs (Folder 254-255)
    - Interstate and Foreign Commerce (Folder 256-257)
    - Interstate Commerce: Mosquito Bill (Box 194, Folder 258)
    - Interstate Commerce: Pay Television (Folder 259)
    - Interstate Commerce: Railroads (Folder 260-261)
    - Judiciary (Folder 262-263)
    - Judiciary (Box 195, Folder 264)
    - Judiciary: Civil Rights (Folder 265)
    - Merchant Marines and Fisheries: Bonnet Small Boat Bill (Folder 266-269)
    - Merchant Marines and Fisheries: Bonner Small Boat Bill (Box 196, Folder 270)
    - Post Office and Civil Service (Folder 271-272)
    - Public Works (Folder 273-274)
    - Rules (Folder 275)
    - Veterans (Folder 276)
    - Ways and Means (Box 197, Folder 277-282)
    - Ways and Means: Recession (Box 198, Folder 283)
    - Ways and Means: Social Security (Folder 284)
    - Ways and Means: Tariff (Folder 285)
    - Ways and Means: Taxation (Folder 286-288)
    - Ways and Means: Trade Agreement (Plywood) (Folder 289-290)
    - Ways and Means: Trade Agreement (Tobacco) (Box 199, Folder 291)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 292-293)
  - 86th Congress 1959-1960
    - Aeronautics and Space Exploration Committee (Folder 294)
    - Agriculture (Folder 295-296)
    - Agriculture: Poultry and Turkeys (Folder 297)
    - Appropriations (Box 200, Folder 298-299)
    - Armed Services (Folder 300)
    - Banking and Currency (Folder 301-302)
    - District of Columbia (Folder 303)
    - Foreign Affairs (Box 201, Folder 304-305)
    - Government Operations (Folder 306)
    - Interior and Insular Affairs (Box 201, Folder 307)
    - Interstate and Foreign Commerce (Folder 308-309)
    - Judiciary (Folder 310-311)
    - Judiciary (Box 202, Folder 312)
    - Judiciary: Civil Rights (Folder 313)
    - Merchant Marines and Fisheries (Folder 314)
    - Post Office and Civil Service (Folder 315-316)
    - Public Works (Folder 317-318)
    - Rules (Folder 319)
    - Un-American Activities (Box 203, Folder 320)
    - Veterans (Folder 321-323)
    - Ways and Means (Folder 324-325)
    - Ways and Means (Box 204, Folder 326-331)
    - Ways and Means: Excise Taxes (Box 205, Folder 332-333)
    - Ways and Means: Shrimp Industry (Folder 334)
    - Ways and Means: Social Security (Folder 335)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 336-338)
  - Speeches in Congress:
    - 1935-1947 (Box 206, Folder 339)
    - ca. 1948-1951 (Folder 340)
    - ca. 1951-1953 (Folder 341)
    - ca. 1954-1957 (Folder 342)
    - ca. 1956 (Folder 343)
    - ca. 1958-1960 (Folder 344)
- Series IV--Correspondence, 1933-1960
  - General Correspondence, A - Z (Box 207 - 292)
  - Answer Copies, 1944-1960 (Box 293 - 332)
- Series V--Personal, 1933-1967?
  - Correspondence
    - 1933 (Box 333, Folder 1-2)
    - 1934 (Folder 3-5)
    - 1934, Financial (Folder 6)
    - 1934, Clippings (Folder 7)
    - 1935-1939 (Box 334, Folder 8)
    - 1940 (Folder 9)
    - 1941 (Folder 10)
    - 1942 (Folder 11)
    - 1943 (Folder 12)
    - 1944 (Folder 13)
    - 1945 (Box 335, Folder 14)
    - 1946 (Folder 15)
    - 1947 (Folder 16)
    - 1948 (Folder 17)
    - 1949 (Folder 18)
    - 1950 (Folder 19)
    - 1950 (Box 336, Folder 20-21)
    - 1951 (Folder 22)
    - 1952 (Folder 23-25)
    - 1952 (Box 337, Folder 26)
    - 1953 (Folder 27-30)
    - 1954 (Folder 31)
    - 1954 (Box 338, Folder 32-33)
    - 1955 (Folder 34-36)
    - 1956 (Folder 37)
    - 1956 (Box 339, Folder 38-40)
    - 1957 (Folder 41-43)
    - 1957 (Box 340, Folder 44)
    - 1958 (Folder 45-49)
    - 1959 (Box 341, Folder 50-52)
    - 1960 (Folder 53-55)
    - 1960 (Box 342, Folder 56-59)
    - 1960, Retirement (Folder 60-61)
    - 1960, Retirement (Box 343-344, Folder 62-74)
    - 1960, Retirement (Box 345, Folder 75-78)
    - Memorabilia (Box 345, Folder 79)
    - Retirement clippings (Folder 80)
    - Retirement clippings (Box 346, Folder 81)
    - Voting records (unnumbered)
  - Speeches
    - Speeches, A (Box 347, Folder 82)
    - B - C (Folder 83)
    - Foreign Aid Background (Folder 84)
    - General (Folder 85-88)
    - Speeches, General (Box 348, Folder 89-93)
    - ca. M - N (Folder 94)
    - N - S (Folder 95)
    - T - Z (Folder 96)
  - Clippings
    - 1934-1937 (Box 349)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 350)
    - 1940 (Box 351)
    - 1941 (Box 352)
    - 1942-1945 (Box 353)
    - 1946-1948 (Box 354)
    - 1949-1952 (Box 355)
    - 1952-1957 (Box 356)
    - 1957-1960 (Box 357)
- Oversize Material
  - Miscellaneous (Opaperfolder 1)
Related Material
David Newton Henderson Papers, 1930-1976
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University